Azeb Haile

(571) 268-5033 azebh.haile@gmail.com Lorton, VA

SUMMARY

Detail oriented with experience in developing full stack Java applications with more than 460 training hours. Focused on perusing a career that will help me to further sharpen my programming skills. Proficient team player with high problem solving and leadership abilities.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Java
- JavaScript
- HTML
- CSS
- Spring Boot
- Spring Data JPA

- Bootstrap
- REST APIs
- SQL
- Unit Testing (JUnit, Mockito)
- SOLID OOP Principles
- Git

WORK EXPERIENCE

iWork's Corporation

Business Analyst

May 2018 – August 2021 McLean, VA

- I was responsible for developing detailed business processes, requirements, and functional designs
- Assisting with development and testing activities across multiple releases
- Develop and review test plans and test cases
- Utilized various SQL commands: create, update, and inner, outer, left, and right joins to update database and retrieve data for analysis and validation
- Write and execute test scripts, and log and communicate defects with developers

Radford University Academic Project

January 2017 - May 2017 Radford, VA

- Created Process, Data and Use Case diagrams by analyzing the business processes using MS-Visio
- Developing test procedures, test plans, and test cases for clients
- Performed data analysis and data validation by writing complex SQL queries using SQL Server management studio

Azeb Haile

(571) 268-5033 azebh.haile@gmail.com Lorton, VA

New River Community College

IT Service Support

August 2015 – January 2017 Dublin, VA

- Worked as a tech support assisting students and faculty member with issues relating to their Computer, Telephones, and Network
- Assisted with other administrative tasks like receiving and mailing out package
- Supported the office by providing an excellent customer service including answers phone calls and responding back to voicemails and keep good records for each voicemail

NASA Langley Research Center

Research Projects Assistant

January 2015 – May 2015 Hampton, VA

- Collecting operational land imager data
- Assisted in the researching phase towards the project to support the team
- Analyzed various technical papers and shared my findings after researching about Digital Elevation Model (DEM) and other tools

Education

Jr. Full Stack Java Developer Bootcamp

January 2022

Generation USA, Denver, CO

Bachelor of Science Information Science and System

May 2018

Radford University, Radford, VA

Certification

Certified JavaScript Developer – W3Schools, 2021